### Contact

n.dutta25@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nandan-dutta-7b26b736 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Machine Learning
Natural Language Processing (NLP)

### Languages

English (Full Professional) hindi Bengali (Full Professional)

## Certifications

Python for Data Science
Statistics 101
Marketing Analytics
Data Analysis with Python
SQL Fundamentals course

# Nandan Dutta

Data Scientist at InstaDataHelp Analytics Services Bengaluru

# Summary

I have an overall experience of 3.5 years In Marketing & Digital Marketing.

Now i'm pursuing the Post Graduate Diploma in Data Science, from Manipal Academy of Higher Studies, which has helped me increase my knowledge in these fields along with data analytics and data modeling.

#### Skills

- Statistical Analysis tools Python, Hadoop, Apache Spark, Data Preprocessing, Statistics, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, Matplotlib, Computer Vision, NLTK, CNN
- Data Visualization: Tableau.
- Others Machine Learning, NLP, Neural Networks, CNN, Deep Learning, Transfer Learning, SQL, Web Development

### **Specialties**

Statistical Analysis, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Mining, Data Analysis, Predictive Modelling, Text Mining, Association rules, Correlation & Regression Analysis, Random Forest, Neural Networks, Clustering (K-means), Decision trees, data extraction, data cleaning, Linear/Logistic Regression, Time series forecasting, Principal component analysis, Business Decision Modelling, Business Analytics, and Strategy

Data is the oil of the 21st century and analytics is the burning house

GitHub: https://github.com/nandandutta

Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/nandandutta

# Experience

InstaDataHelp Analytics Services
Data Scientist
April 2020 - Present (5 months)
Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Collaborate & Contribute

Data Scientist || Project Management

May 2020 - Present (4 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

An initiative we a team of 12 budding and enthusiastic DATA learners have decided to start an initiative for helping out companies who are unable to hire young DATA Scientists like us and help them out with their projects at no cost service

#### **VBG**

Founder

June 2017 - Present (3 years 3 months)

Kolkata Area, India

VBG is an Esports Platform where competitors (players)will play against each other using PC, PlayStation or other game consoles.

InfoAxon Technologies Limited
Digital Marketing Executive
September 2018 - July 2019 (11 months)
Noida Area, India

Lead Generation, Email Marketing, SEO, Google Adwords Handle CRM, Handle Social Media Accounts, Participate In RFP Making Research and content strategy

#### Jio

Premium Relationship Manager March 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 4 months) Kolkata, West Bengal, India

Acquisition and on boarding.

- # Act as a dedicated single point of contact for affluent and HNI clients.
- # Proactive monitoring of clients usage pattern of voice and data along with value added services.
- # Retention of the HNI clients.
- # To understand client's needs & requirements and accordingly position products & services and do

Upsell and cross sell.

# To contact clients periodically and determine if they are satisfied with the service.

# To work in special assignment assigned by the state HQ and ensure in time delivery of the same.

#### FOROPICK TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD.

Co Founder

January 2016 - March 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Kolkata Area, India

Generate new prospects for business by attending assigned appointments

Meet clients and give presentation on company product and services to clients.

Establish good relationship with prospective clients, closures of sales for revenue generation. Solving client's problems, queries to retain the assigned accounts.

Focusing on sales growth / more clients' acquisition for the portal.

Responsible for delivering the desired result by achieving the assigned sales target Identifying, developing and nurturing new markets by implementing innovative marketing strategies for boosting sales Conducting extensive study of market trends / mapping requirements for further

business growth Executing sales plans devised by the management / contributing towards the growth of business revenue

with various vendor for the event.

- Generate new prospects for business by attending assigned appointments
   Meet clients and give
   presentation on company product and services to clients.
- Coordinate with Sponsors & Build relationship with the various organisation like sony, gigabyte,
   xbox, etc.

# Education

Manipal Academy of Higher Education - MAHE, Bengaluru PGD, Data science · (2019 - 2020)

West Bengal University of Technology, Kolkata Bachelor's Degree · (2011 - 2015)

## Contai Model Institution

Science · (2009 - 2011)